Guide to the Institute of Pacific Relations Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Part III: Files of Individuals
  - Part III.3: W.L. Holland
    - 1951
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1951 (Box 336)
      - Rockefeller Foundation--General (Box 336)
      - Royal Institute
        - Miss Cleeve (Box 336)
        - Macadam (Box 336)
        - Olver (Box 336)
      - S--Miscellaneous (Box 337)
      - Sansom, Sir George (Box 337)
      - Shahn, Tillie G. (Box 337)
      - Social Science Research Council (Box 337)
      - Spaeth, Dean Carl B. (Box 337)
      - Spencer, ProJoseph E (Box 337)
      - Staff (Box 337)
      - Swope, Gerard (Box 337)
      - Swygard, Dr. Kline R. (Box 337)
      - T--Miscellaneous (Box 337)
      - Taylor, George (Box 337)
      - Thomas, S.B. (Box 337)
      - U--Miscellaneous (Box 337)
      - United Service to China (Box 337)
      - U.S. National Commission for UNESCO (Box 337)
      - USSR Council (Box 337)
      - V--Miscellaneous (Box 337)
      - Van Nieuwenhuijze, Dr. C.A.O. (Box 337)
      - Vinacke, Harold (Box 337)
      - W--Miscellaneous (Box 337)
      - Watumull Foundation (Box 337)
      - Whitney Foundation (Box 337)
      - Wint, Guy (Box 337)
      - X-Y-Z—Miscellaneous (Box 337)
  - Part III.4: A. Kohlberg
    - Statements about the work and program of the IPR, Undated (Box 338)
    - Statement on Charges by Alfred Kohlberg, Undated (Box 338)
    - Notices to Members Re: Meeting for past years, 1942-1944 (Box 338)
    - Kohlberg, 1943-1945 (Box 338)
    - Board and Executive Committee, 1944, 1946 (Box 338)
    - Legal Documents, 1945-1946 (Box 338)
    - Kohlberg, 1945-1947 (Box 338)
    - Board of Trustees, 1944 December 19 (Box 338)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 338)
    - Analysis of Kohlberg's Charges, 1945 February (Box 338)
    - Comments on Kohlberg's Attacks, 1945 (Box 338)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 338)
    - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1945 (Box 338)
    - Legal Correspondence, 1945 (Box 338)
    - Willits' Proposal, 1945 (Box 338)
    - Letters to Members, 1945 March 27 (Box 338)
    - Board of Trustees, 1946 July 29 (Box 338)
    - Board of Trustees, 1946 September 24 (Box 338)
    - Chart, 1946 (Box 338)
    - Correspondence, 1946
      - Court Trial, 1946 September 24 (Box 339)
      - Carter, Edward C., 1946 (Box 339)
      - Kohlberg, 1946 (Box 339)
      - Lattimore, 1946 (Box 339)
      - Legal Correspondence, 1946 (Box 339)
      - Letter to Editors, 1946 September 22 (Box 339)
      - Membership, 1946 (Box 339)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1946 (Box 339)
      - Officers of Amco, 1946 August 13 (Box 339)
      - Sproul, Carter, Emeny statement of September 23, 1946 (Box 339)
      - Analysis of Kohlberg Document, 1947 (Box 339)
      - Board of Trustees, 1947 January 16 (Box 339)
      - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 339)
      - Correspondence on Kohlberg meetings to members, 1947 (Box 339)
      - Executive Committee Comments, 1947 (Box 339)
      - Favorable Comments, 1947 (Box 339)
      - Kohlberg
        - General, 1947 (Folders 1-5) (Box 339)
        - General, 1947 (Folders 6-8) (Box 340)
      - Legal Correspondence, 1947 (Box 340)
      - Minnesota, 1947 (Box 340)
      - Plain Talk, 1947 January 3 (Box 340)
      - Proxies--General, 1947 (2 Folders) (Box 340)
      - Proxies Signed, 1947 (Box 340)
      - Proxies to Kohlberg, 1947 (Box 340)
      - Proxies with regrets, 1947 (Box 340)
      - Proxies with reservation, 1947 (Box 340)
      - Kohlberg--General, 1948-1949 (3 Folders) (Box 340)
- Part IV: McCarran Committee Files
  - Part IV.1: Committee Files
    (Boxes 341-375 IPR documents subpoenaed by McCarran Committee (A-Z), and the proceedings of the McCarran Committee (filed under "McCarran Committee," in Boxes 365-367) )
    - A-Miscellaneous (Box 341)
    - Address List (Box 341)
    - Amerasia (Box 341)
    - Amerasia Magazine (Box 341)
    - American Association of University Women (Box 341)
    - American Committee for Non-participation in Japanese Aggression (Box 341)
    - American Council
      - Annual Meeting (Box 341)
      - Contribution (Box 341)
      - Education (Box 341)
      - Executive Committee Correspondence (l) (Box 341)
      - Executive Committee Correspondence (2) (Box 342)
      - Field, Frederick, (3 Folders) (Box 342)
      - Finances (Box 342)
      - General (Box 342)
      - Language Course (Box 342)
      - Nominating Committee (Box 342)
      - Regional Conference (Box 343)
      - Rocky Mountain Region (Box 343)
      - San Francisco Office (Box 343)
      - Secretaryship (Box 343)
      - Shop Committee (Box 343)
      - Staff (Box 343)
      - Staff Memoranda (Box 343)
      - Washington Office (Box 343)
    - American Council of Learned Society--Graves, Mortimer (Box 343)
    - American Institute
      - Annual Reports (Box 343)
      - Board, 1947 (Box 343)
      - Contributions (Box 343)
      - Executive Committee (Box 343)
      - De. Elisseeff, Serge (Box 343)
      - Material Sent to IPR Members (Box 344)
      - New York Study Group, 1949 (Box 344)
      - Nominating Committee (Box 344)
      - Pacific Relations (Box 344)
      - Staff (Box 344)
      - Washington Office (Box 344)
    - American League Against War and Fascism (Box 344)
    - Austern, Hilda (Box 344)
    - Avery, Sewell L. (Box 344)
    - Barnes, Joseph (Box 344)
    - Barnes, Kathleen (Box 344)
    - Barnett, Eugene E. (Box 344)
    - Barnett, Robert (Box 344)
    - Barton, R.F. (Box 344)
    - Bates, M.S. (Box 344)
    - Bibliographies, Far Eastern, 1949 (Box 345)
    - Biographies Institute of Pacific Relations (Box 345)
    - Bisson, T.A. (Box 345)
    - Books (Box 345)
    - Book and Magazine Union (Box 345)
    - Borg, Dorothy (Box 345)
    - Bowman, Isiah--American Geographical Society, New York (Box 345)
    - Browder, Earl (Box 345)
    - C--Miscellaneous (Box 345)
    - Cambridge Meeting, Summary (Box 345)
    - Canadian Institute of International Affairs (Box 345)
    - Carlson, Evans F. (Box 345)
    - Carter, Edward C.
      - Correspondence (Folders 1-4) (Box 345)
      - Correspondence (Folders 5-11) (Box 346)
      - Correspondence (Folder 12) (Box 347)
      - ECAFE Consultant (Box 347)
      - Letters of Reference Introduction (Box 347)
      - Letters to Dr. Willits (Box 347)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 347)
      - Notes and Memoranda (Box 347)
      - Some Secretariat Letter (Box 347)
      - Soviet Union (Box 347)
    - Carter, Ruth (Box 347)
    - Carter, William (Box 347)
    - Chapman, Abraham (Box 347)
    - Chatham House IPR Committee (Box 347)
    - Chen, Han Seng (Box 347)
    - Chi, Ch'ao-Ting (Box 347)
    - China--General (2 Folders). (Box 347)
    - China Institute of Pacific Relations (l) (Box 347)
    - China Institute of Pacific Relations (2) (Box 348)
    - China Council
      - Dr. Yen, W.W., Chairman (Box 348)
      - Yu-wan, Liu, Secretary (Box 348)
    - Chinese Language (Box 348)
    - Chinese Language Course (2 Folders) (Box 348)
    - Chinese Language School (2 Folders) (Box 348)
    - Christian, J.L. (Box 348)
    - Claxton, Booke "Canadian-American Relations” (Box 348)
    - Columbia University Naval School (Box 348)
    - Conference
      - Asilomar, 1946 (Box 348)
      - Alderbrook, 1938 (Box 348)
      - Annapolis-Regional, 1947 (Box 348)
      - Banff, 1932 (Box 349)
      - Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1939 (Box 349)
      - Coronado, California, 1947 (Box 349)
      - Delegations and General Information (Box 349)
      - Hot Springs, Virginia
        - Appraisals, 1945 (Box 349)
        - Carnegie Corporation (Box 349)
        - China (Box 349)
        - Claremont (Box 349)
        - Comments and Criticisms (Box 349)
        - Draft Agendas and Working Papers (Box 349)
        - Korea, 1945 (Box 349)
        - Personnel (Box 349)
        - Preliminary Meeting of American Delegation (Box 349)
        - Union Soviet Socialist Republic (Box 349)
        - United Kingdom (Box 349)
        - United States (Box 349)
        - Who's Who (Box 349)
        - List of Delegates and Committee (Box 349)
      - India, 1950 (11th IPR Conference) (Box 349)
      - London (10th International) (Box 350)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 350)
      - Mount Tremblant, Canada, 1942, (2 Folders) (Box 350)
      - On the Far East in Teachers Education (Box 350)
      - Princeton (Box 350)
      - Virginia Beach (Box 350)
      - Washington, D.C., 1938 (Box 350)
      - Yosemite, 1930 (Box 350)
    - Corbett, P.E.--Post War World (Box 350)
    - Council of Inquiry into Far Eastern Affairs (Box 350)
    - Cox, E.E.
      - Committee Hearing Materials (Folders 1-2) (Box 350)
      - Committee Hearing Materials (Folder 3) (Box 351)
    - Currie, Lauchlin (Box 351)
    - Daniel, Judith (Box 351)
    - Datta, Rena (Box 351)
    - Davies, Jojn P. (Box 351)
    - Debuchi, Ambassador Katsuji (Box 351)
    - Dennett, Raymond, (2 Folders) (Box 351)
    - Dennett, Raymond--Personal (Box 351)
    - Directories and Reference Books--IPR Entries (Box 351)
    - Duggan, Lawrence (Box 351)
    - Economist Article, 1952 (Box 351)
    - Diplomatic Machinery and Armaments in the Pacific (Box 351)
    - Emeny, Brooke (Box 351)
    - Epstein, Israel (Box 351)
    - Ewing, Ethel E. (Box 351)
    - F--Miscellaneous (Box 352)
    - Fahs, Charles B. (Box 352)
    - Fairbank, John K. (Box 352)
    - Fairfax-Cholmeley, Elsie (Box 352)
    - Farley, Miriam (Box 352)
    - Federated Press (Box 352)
    - Federal Reserve (Box 352)
    - Field, Frederick V.
      - General, 1932-1938 (Folders 1-4) (Box 352)
      - General, 1932-1938 (Folders 5-12) (Box 353)
      - General, 1935-1951 (Folders 13-19) (Box 354)
      - War Memo, 1939 (Box 354)
    - Finances
      - Cancelled Checks (Box 355)
      - Research Programs (Box 355)
    - Finkelstein, Lawrence (Box 355)
    - Fisher, Galen M. (Box 355)
    - Foreign Policy Association (Box 355)
    - Friedman, Julian R. (Box 355)
    - G--Miscellaneous (Box 355)
    - Grajdansev, Andrew (Box 355)
    - Graves, Mortimer (Box 355)
    - Greene, Jerome D. (Box 355)
    - Greene, Katrine R.C. (Box 355)
    - Guthman, Renee (Box 355)
    - Hiss, Alger (Box 355)
    - Holland, William L.
      - Correspondence (Folder l) (Box 355)
      - Correspondence (Folders 2-8) (Box 356)
      - Correspondence (Folders 9-10) (Box 357)
      - Study on the Future of IPR, 1950-1951 (Box 357)
    - Hornbeck, Stanley K. (Box 357)
    - Hsu, Y.Y. (Box 357)
    - Industrial Japan, 1941 (Box 357)
    - Inparel, 1939 (Box 357)
    - International Cultural Relations Society (Box 357)
    - International Secretariat Inquiry, 1938 (Box 357)
      (Special Research Project)
    - International Secretariat--Shanghai Office (Box 357)
    - Inquiry, IPR, 1939 (Box 357)
    - Ishii, Viscount Kikujiro (Box 357)
    - J--Miscellaneous (Box 357)
    - Jaffe, Philip (Box 357)
    - Japan
      - General (Folders 1-2) (Box 357)
      - General (Folder 3) (Box 358)
      - Kokusai Bunka Shinkokai (Box 358)
      - Postwar Treatment (Box 358)
    - Japanese American Courier, Seattle (Box 358)
    - Japanese-American Relations Conference, Honolulu, 1953 (Box 358)
    - Japanese Council
      - Correspondence (Box 358)
      - General ( 2 Folders) (Box 358)
      - Ishii, Viscount Kikujiro (Box 358)
      - Ishimoto, K. Baroness (Box 358)
      - Admission (Box 358)
      - Matsukata, Saburo (Box 358)
      - Members--Biographical Information (Box 358)
      - Minutes (Box 358)
      - Nasu, Shiroshi (Box 358)
      - Newsletters (C. Tyler, 1933-1934) (Box 358)
      - Nitobe, Inazo (Box 359)
      - Saionji, Kinkazu (Box 359)
      - Saito, Soichi (Box 359)
      - Takaki, Yasaka (Box 359)
      - Takayanagio, ProKenzo (Box 359)
      - Prince Tokugawu (Box 359)
      - Tsurumi, Yusuke (Box 359)
      - Uramatsu, Samataro (Box 359)
      - Ushiba, Tomohiko (2 Folders) (Box 359)
    - Japanese Consulate - New York (Box 360)
    - Japanese Embassy - Washington (Box 360)
    - Japanese Studies Project, 1933-1934 (Box 360)
    - Japanese Studies Project--ProTakaki (Box 360)
    - Japanese Translations
      - Asahi (Box 360)
      - International Law (Box 360)
    - Jessup, Philip C.
      - (Folders 1-6) (Box 360)
      - Conference (Box 360)
      - Kohlberg Period (Box 360)
    - Jones, Joseph (Box 361)
    - Kato, Kanju (Box 361)
    - Kizer, B.H. (Box 361)
    - Kohlberg, Alfred-- Charges Against IPR
      - Analysis (Box 361)
      - Related Correspondence (Box 361)
    - Kuno, Prof.--Japanese Institution of Learning Related Correspondence (Box 361)
    - L--Miscellaneous (Box 361)
    - Landsberger, Alfred (Box 361)
    - Lasker, Bruno (Box 361)
    - Lattimore, Eleanor (Box 361)
    - Lattimore, Owen
      - (Folders 1-2) (Box 361)
      - (Folders 3-10) (Box 362)
      - Carbons of Letters (Folders 1-7) (Box 363)
    - Lilienthal, Philip E. (Box 364)
    - Lindsay, Michael--Communism in China (Box 364)
    - Little, Herbert S. (Box 364)
    - Liu, Yu-wan - China (Box 364)
    - Lockwood, W.W.
      - Correspondence, (3 Folders) (Box 364)
      - Correspondence with the Government (Box 364)
    - Loomis, Charles F. (Box 364)
    - Lorwin, Lewis (Box 364)
    - Lorwin, Val (Box 364)
    - Luce, Henry R. (Box 364)
    - M--Miscellaneous (Box 364)
    - Mc—Miscellaneous (Box 364)
    - McCarran Committee
      - Comments and Clippings (2 Folders) (Box 365)
      - Correspondence (Box 365)
      - Evidence
        - Copies of IPR Records (2 Folders) (Box 365)
        - Photostats, 1930-1946 (14 Folders) (Box 365)
        - Photostats, 1947-1951 (5 Folders) (Box 366)
      - IPR Correspondence
        - Staff (Box 366)
        - Trustees (Box 366)
      - IPR Response to Committee Report (Box 366)
      - Press. Release (Box 366)
      - Senate Sub-committee Documents (Box 366)
      - Statements
        - Carter, Edward C. (Box 366)
        - General (Box 366)
        - Holland, William L. (Box 367)
        - Lattimore, Owen (Box 367)
        - Testimonials and Pro-IPR Letters (Box 367)
    - McLauchlin, Alfred (and Mrs.) (Box 367)
    - MacAdam, Ivison S.--Chatham House (Box 367)
    - Mandel, William (Box 367)
    - Maps and related Military Information (Box 367)
    - Matsuo, Matsuhei (Box 367)
    - Mayeda, T.--Japan Institute (Box 367)
    - Miscellaneous Unidentifiable (Box 367)
    - Mitchell, Kate (Box 367)
    - Moore, Harriet L. (Box 367)
    - Morris, Robert (Box 368)
    - Murphy, J.M. (Box 368)
    - National Secretaries (Box 368)
    - Nehru, Pandit Jawaharlal (Box 368)
    - Norman, E. Herbert (Box 368)
    - Officers of Pacific Relations Institute (Box 368)
    - P--Miscellaneous (Box 368)
    - Pacific Affairs
      - Baltimore Office--Owen Lattimore (Box 368)
      - General (Box 368)
      - Greenberg, Michael (Box 368)
      - Lattimore, Owen (Box 368)
      - Peking Office
        - Finances (Box 368)
        - Lattimore, Owen (Folder l) (Box 368)
        - Lattimore, Owen (Folder 2) (Box 369)
    - Pacific Council
      - Expense (Box 369)
      - General (2 Folders) (Box 369)
      - Minutes (Box 369)
      - Salaries, 1935-1942 (Box 369)
    - Pacific House (Box 369)
    - Pacific Relation--Study of its Future, 1950 (Box 370)
    - Pearson, Drew vs. J.R. McCarthy--D. Surine Deposition (Box 370)
    - Price, Harry B. (Box 370)
    - Princeton Conference
      - 1941 (Box 370)
      - 1942 (Box 370)
      - 1946 (Box 371)
      - 1952 (Box 371)
    - Princeton University Press--Smith, Datus (Box 371)
    - Publication List (Box 371)
    - Publication Program (Box 371)
    - Purcell., Victor (Box 371)
    - Pyke, Richard (Box 371)
    - Q--Miscellaneous (Box 371)
    - R--Miscellaneous (Box 371)
    - Radio (Box 371)
    - Rockefeller Fellowship, 1941 (Box 371)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 371)
    - Rosinger, L.--Applications (Box 371)
    - Royal Institute of International Affairs (Box 371)
    - Russian Language School, Berkeley (Box 371)
    - Russian War Relief (Box 371)
    - Sachs, Alexander--Confidential Report Suggestions (Box 371)
    - Soviet Exchange
      - Academy of Social Science Library (Box 372)
      - Committee on Soviet Change (Box 372)
      - International Agrarian Institute (Box 372)
      - Library of the Social Sciences (Box 372)
      - Publications (2 Folders) (Box 372)
      - USSR Society for Cultural Relations (Box 372)
    - Stanford Conference Summary, 1952 (Box 372)
    - Stein, Gunther--Business with East Asia (Box 373)
    - Stewart, Marguerite Ann (Box 373)
    - Stewart, Marguerite Ann--Land of the Soviets (Box 373)
    - T--Miscellaneous (Box 373)
    - Tanaka Memorial (Box 373)
    - Tarr, Edgar J.--IPR Treasurer (Box 373)
    - Tax Exemption (Box 373)
    - Taylor, George (Box 373)
    - Teacher's Seminars--Study Outlines, Bibliographies (Box 373)
    - Thorner, Daniel and Alice--The Shaping of Modern India (Box 373)
    - Tsuru, S. (Box 373)
    - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (USSR)
      - General (Folders 1-2) (Box 373)
      - General (Folder 3) (Box 374)
    - USSR Council, (2 Folders) (Box 374)
    - United Nations (Box 374)
    - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA) (Box 374)
    - United States Government--Office of War Information and Board of Economic Warfare (Box 374)
    - United States
      - Immigration and Naturalization (Box 374)
      - Industrial Training for Personnel from Ecafe Countries (Box 374)
      - State Department (Box 374)
    - Veatch, Roy (Box 375)
    - Veterans Programs (Box 375)
    - Vincent, John Carter (Box 375)
    - Von Trott, Adam (Box 375)
    - Walker, Richard (Box 375)
    - Warner, Kenneth O.--Problems of Federalism in Australia (Box 375)
    - Webster Publishing Co. (Box 375)
    - Welles, Sumner (Box 375)
    - Wells, Henry (Box 375)
    - Winfield, Gerald--China, the Land and the People (Box 375)
    - Wittfogel, Karl A. (Box 375)
    - Yasuo, Nagaharu
      - Bibliographies (Box 375)
      - General (Box 375)
      - Immigration (Box 375)
  - Part IV.2: Releases
    (Letters, Statements, Testimonials, Excerpts, News articles and Editorials for and against McCarran Committee Investigation issued by the IPR.)
    - Studies Japan, 1925-1951 (Box 376)
    - A personal view of Institute of Pacific Relations, 1927-1952 (Box 376)
    - American Institute of Pacific Relation Board of Trustees, 1927-1951 (Box 376)
    - American Institute of Pacific Relations Executive Board, 1927-1951 (Box 376)
    - Documents on Mr. Lattimore Letter, 1938 July 30 (Box 376)
    - Carter, Edward C., 1938 July 18 (Box 376)
    - Field to Ferguson, 1939 September 13 (Box 376)
    - Kohlberg Analysis, 1945 February (Box 376)
    - Testimonial, Hart to Dennett, 1945 March 15 (Box 376)
    - Testimonial, McConaughy to Kohlberg, 1946 August 13 (Box 376)
    - Letter to Trustees and Attempt to stifle IPR, 1947 March 17 (Box 376)
    - Whitney Letter re: Bisson, 1947 May 8 (Box 376)
    - Announcement of Lucknow Conference, 1950 April 6 (Box 376)
    - Letter to the Editor, 1950 April 13 (Box 376)
    - President Allen’s Statement, 1950 April 21 (Box 376)
    - Man Behind Man Accusing Lattimore (Washington Post), 1950 April 23 (Box 376)
    - Is There A China Lobby?, 1950 April 30 (Box 376)
    - Lattimore Statement re: Pacific Affairs to Tydings Committee, 1950 May (Box 376)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations Executive and Finance Committee for Information, 1950 June 8 (Box 376)
    - Excerpts from State Department Employee Loyalty Investigation February 1951 Some Facts about I.P.R., 1950 July 20 (Box 376)
    - Holland Statement, 1951 February 9 (Box 376)
    - The Trustees and Members, 1951 February 14 (Box 376)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations Statement, 1951 February 16 (Box 376)
    - Nation Editorial, 1951 February 17 (Box 376)
    - My Dear Senator Ferguson, 1951 February 21 (Box 376)
    - My Dear Senator Mundt, 1951 February 23 (Box 376)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations Statement, 1951 February 26 (Box 376)
    - Editorial from San Francisco Chronicle, 1951 February 27 (Box 376)
    - To Trustees and Members, 1951 February 27 (Box 376)
    - Letter to John Wood, 1951 March 8 (Box 376)
    - American Institute Protests Un-American Listing, 1951 March 9 (Box 376)
    - To the Far Eastern Survey Subscribers, 1951 March 15 (Box 376)
    - Honolulu Star-Bulletin, 1951 March 16 (Box 376)
    - New Trustees, 1951 March 23 (Box 376)
    - Trustees, Members and Subscribers, 1951 March 30 (Box 376)
    - Excerpts from Publishers Weekly, 1951 May 5 (Box 376)
    - Statement re: Institute of Pacific Relations by 21 educators, missionaries, etc., 1951 May 21 (Box 376)
    - Post Reprint on MacArthur Rally, 1951 May 23 (Box 376)
    - Trustees and Members of the American Institute of Pacific Relations, 1951 May 25 (Box 376)
    - To Trustees and Members re: China Story, 1951 July 21 (Box 376)
    - Pacific Institute issues Statement on Senate Hearings, 1951 July 25 (Box 376)
    - American Institute of Pacific Relations Trustees, 1951 July 26 (Box 376)
    - Oven Lattimore Statement, 1951 July 26 (Box 376)
    - Pacific Institute "backed by Leading Educators, 1951 July 26 (Box 376)
    - Some of the persons vho whave made testimonials in support of the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1951 July 26 (Box 376)
    - Comments on McCarran Subcommittee Attack. 1951 August (Box 377)
    - Truth and Untruth Preliminary Draft, 1951 August (Box 377)
    - IPR Refutes Barmine’s Testimony, 1951 August 1 (Box 377)
    - Second Statement by Oven Lattimore, 1951 August 1 (Box 377)
    - Pacific Institute Refutes Espionage Allegations, 1951 August 9 (Box 377)
    - Contemptible Attack on Mr. Norman (Ottawa Morning Citizen), 1951 August 11 (Box 377)
    - McCarran Follows McCarthy—Economist, 1951 August 11 (Box 377)
    - Smear Come North (Toronto Globe and Mail), 1951 August 11 (Box 377)
    - Bently Allegations Refuted by IPR, 1951 August 14 (Box 377)
    - One Under Every Bed (Ottawa Morning Citizen), 1951 August 14 (Box 377)
    - Kohlberg to American Institute of Pacific Relations Trustees, 1951 August 20 (Box 377)
    - To Trustees and Members, 1951 August 20 (Box 377)
    - Pacific Institute Denounces Budenz Testimony, 1951 August 23 (Box 377)
    - Fairbank to McCarran, 1951 August 30 (Box 377)
    - Lockwood, William to New York Times re: Firbank, 1951 September 11 (Box 377)
    - Barnes, Kathleen to Holland, 1951 September 12 (Box 377)
    - Lamont to McCarran, 1951 September 15 (Box 377)
    - Stein to Holland, 1951 September 15 (Box 377)
    - Kizer Affidavit, 1951 September 17 (Box 377)
    - Excerpt from New York Post re: McCarthy, 1951 September 18 (Box 377)
    - Telegram to McCarran, 1951 September 18 (Box 377)
    - Carter requests Access to Correspondence, 1951 September 18 (Box 377)
    - Lamont to McCarran, 1951 September 26 (Box 377)
    - Statement by W.L. Holland on the China Aid Council, 1951 October (Box 377)
    - Our Job in the Pacific, 1951 October (Box 377)
    - Statement and Testimonials by Gerard Swope, 1951 October (Box 377)
    - "War-Time China" by Maxwell So Stewart, 1951 October (Box 377)
    - Rosinger Refutes Stassen's Testimony, 1951 October 2 (Box 377)
    - Statement by Owen Lattimore, 1951 October 2 (Box 377)
    - Part II of Statement made by Philip C. Jessup, 1951 October 3-5 (Box 377)
    - Fairbank, John to Swope Gerard, 1951 October 4 (Box 377)
    - Barnes, Joseph to Holland, William L., 1951 October 5 (Box 377)
    - Stewart, Max to Holland, William L., 1951 October 5 (Box 377)
    - The Trustees of the American Institute of Pacific Relations, 1951 October 5 (Box 377)
    - Twenty Distinguished Americans, 1951 October 6 (Box 377)
    - Salisbury, Laurence E. To Senator Pat McCarran, 1951 October 7 (Box 377)
    - Memorandum by Lawrence K. Rosinger, 1951 October 8 (Box 377)
    - China Aid Council-Osborne, Ernest to Senator Pat McCarran, 1951 October 9 (Box 377)